<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Student Life on Enoch Yu (유에녹)</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/categories/student-life/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Student Life on Enoch Yu (유에녹)</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/categories/student-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Accepting Failure: After Giving It My All</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/post/post3/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/post/post3/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post discusses about the recent emotional deterioration that I faced. If you are currently undergoing a challenge, I sincerely wish you to cheer up!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-disqualification&#34;&gt;The Disqualification
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One may wonder: how big of a challenge can a high school student face? Well, I believe regardless of age, countless people encounter emotional challenges. For instance, failing an exam, receiving rejections, and breaking-up with the significant other may cause distress. As a student who wishes to major in pure mathematics, disqualifying from the second stage of team selecting process for the IMO (International Mathematical Olympiad) hit me hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most students in South Korea prepare from the age of 7 to become a representative for the IMO. While I wasn’t as intensely prepared compared to the other students, I can proudly say that I gave it my all for past 11 months. I genuinly spent at least 5 hours to at most 10 hours on solving and studying Olympiad style problems without missing a single day. After passing the first stage of the seleting process, I studied harder for the second stage. Because I knew that I wasn’t as good as the past representatives, my goal for the year 2025 was to qualify to participate in APMO (Asian Pacific Mathematical Olympiad) by passing the second stage exam of KMO (Korean Mathematical Olympiad). Unfortunately, I was not able to make it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overcoming-the-challenge&#34;&gt;Overcoming the Challenge
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Failing from KMO Stage II has more meaning than just failing for me. I was genuinely worried about my future applications for math programs and motivation to study further for Olympiad mathematics. Moreover, the biggest challenge was that I was not able to fulfill the expectation of other people. Everytime people ask for the result, I need to say that I could not make it. What’s more painful than failing the exam is the fact that I need to say unfavorable result outloud numerous times for next few days even if I am aware that I couldn’t make it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-positive-mindset&#34;&gt;The Positive Mindset
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a result, I decided to change my mindset. If anyone asks me about the result, I proudly say that I couldn’t make it. Because I have my final chance next year, I will take the failure from this year as my main motivation. In regard to future applications for math programs, I believe not all participants in summer programs are IMO gold medalist. I began to understand silence radiance with the fact that my hard works and myself are just a tiny bit away from getting a spark for huge fire. Although I cannot make the fire right away, I believe that smoke, or effort, is an essential indicator that the fire is actually starting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The positive mindset to turn failure into a chance and shame into a motivation allowed me to prepare myself for bigger challenges. Moreover, while walking down the street, I realized that staying in distress does not change the result. It is only the positive mindset that changes the failure into chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s really not the end of the world. I believe nothing is impossible if we have the positive mindset to create the future!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;comments-note&#34;&gt;
  💬 &lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  Please don&#39;t hesitate to comment any questions or feedback!!
  Posting a comment requires a free GitHub account :))
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>[README] From the Beginning: My First Post</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/post/post1/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/post/post1/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!! Welcome to my personal blog where I post about various topics! I am a student from South Korea, and is currently attending Laurel Springs School. Please check out my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@enochyu_official/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/enochyu-official&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for more information!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-started-to-blog&#34;&gt;Why I Started to Blog
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Frankly, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t always confident in writing. Although I am comfortable with using English, the thought that I do not sound like a &lt;strong&gt;native speaker&lt;/strong&gt;, when using casual term, kicks in. &lt;em&gt;Is my grammar wrong? Is my word choice not ideal? Am I using the word in a wrong way?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all concerns, two reason allowed me to write this first post. The first reason is to overcome challenges that I face when using English. I remember a Christian missionary emphasizing the following quote in a retreat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do nothing, nothing will happen. So challenge yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The message from the missionary hit me hard, and allowed me to reflect myself again. I noticed Enoch who is afraid to use &lt;em&gt;casual&lt;/em&gt; English because he may not sound like a native speaker. Writing academic texts are no problem. Therefore, I decided to write my blog in casual way to try and overcome the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason for blogging is to record my academic journey. I found blogging as one of the best method to organize what I learned and share publically. I decided to publish my journey and resources publically in case someone finds them useful and to potentially receive any feedback. Here, I will mainly be blogging about learning Linux and Capture the Flag (CTF). I hope to see improved self when I look back at my posts one day!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below are the areas that I dedicate to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a student pursuing to major in pure mathematics, I love to write about math and share solutions. Although I have published all my works in GitHub, this section is dedicated to topics that I was not able to post publically in GitHub. Maybe I can share my progress and stories behind the scenes :))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;computer-science&#34;&gt;Computer Science
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Broadly speaking, I first gained interest in computer science in my second semester of high school freshman year. I first encountered LaTeX while submitting applications for various Math Summer Programs. After learning to write with Overleaf, I gained interests in coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Briefly speaking, I found a &lt;em&gt;fake proof&lt;/em&gt; to Fermat&amp;rsquo;s Last Theorem; I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize that I have a flaw in the proof before I started writing my proof in research paper style. Before writing the proof in Overleaf, I was concerned about uploading the draft in cloud. It &lt;strong&gt;does not&lt;/strong&gt; mean that I don&amp;rsquo;t trust Overleaf staffs and people envolved with cloud. I realized that countless mathematicians use local LaTeX and code editors to write their drafts. So why not do the same..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, it &lt;strong&gt;does not&lt;/strong&gt; mean that I do not trust Microsoft. However, I am not a big fan of telemetry involved with Visual Studio Code. Therefore, while looking for an open source code editor, I came across &lt;em&gt;Neovim&lt;/em&gt;. Well, first of all, setting up for Neovim and most open source code editors is not an easy task for someone new to computer science. After few hours of fighting with terminal, I finally have Neovim as my main code editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debugging has different nuance from solving math problem. In other words, I found a new type of challenge!! Especially, CTF came into my sight. Although some may say it is too late to start CTF as a high school sophomore, I never think it&amp;rsquo;s too late to learn anything. Yes, I acknowledge that I might not be able to win competitions as a high school student because there are people who studied much more than me and I didn&amp;rsquo;t start CTF as early as I started my journey for math. However, I believe investigating my time in cybersecurity and how computers operate would benefit me in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;student-life&#34;&gt;Student Life
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I express and organize my thoughts through words, I would like to share my student life. Espescially as a student from an online high school, many people wonder about my daily schedule. Everything is here!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;miscellaneous&#34;&gt;Miscellaneous
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As one may have guessed, this category is for posts that do not fit to categories above :))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;comments-note&#34;&gt;
  💬 &lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  Please don&#39;t hesitate to comment any questions or feedback!!
  Posting a comment requires a free GitHub account :))
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
